I've completely automated my social media posts using MAKE. Just check the automatically gathered content, and AI will craft posts for each platform.
MAKEを使ってSNS投稿を完全自動化しました。（ツイッター、リンクトイン、インスタなど）自動収集された記事をチェックするだけで、AIが各プラットフォームに合った文章を生成してくれます。
It even handles the posting for me.
さらに、投稿まで自動で行ってくれます。
Makes social media posting so much easier, right?
SNSの投稿が本当に簡単になりますよね？
Lately, you've probably heard that social media marketing is no longer optional, but essential.
最近、SNSマーケティングはもはや選択ではなく必須だという話をよく耳にすると思います。
Many ordinary workers are now making as much from their social media activity after work as they do from their primary job.
実際、最近では普通の会社員でも、退勤後のSNS活動だけで本業の年収に匹敵するほどの収入を得ている事例がかなり多いんです。
Social media seems to be the best way to build your personal brand or create a side hustle.
それだけ、セルフブランディングや将来の副業に活用する上で、SNSは本当に最高の手段だと思います。
However, those of you who have tried it know that managing social media is not easy.
しかし、SNSの運営が決して簡単ではないことは、経験した方ならよくご存知でしょう。
It's quite a burden to constantly come up with new ideas and create posts tailored for each platform.
毎日新しいアイデアを思いつき、各プラットフォームの特性に合わせて投稿するのは、並大抵のことではありません。
But, did you know that overseas marketers are already using AI automation systems to operate their social media accounts and achieve great results, without lifting a finger?
しかし、海外のマーケターたちは既にAI自動化システムを活用して、手を煩わせることなくSNSを運営し、大きな成果を上げているという事実をご存知ですか？
Yes.
はい。
Many of them are easily publishing more than one post per day.
1日1投稿はもちろん、それ以上のコンテンツ発行も楽々とこなしている人が多いんです。
Today, I'll show you how to set up a system that automatically posts on your social media accounts with just one setup.
そこで今日は、一度設定するだけでSNSへの投稿が自動化されるシステムを作る方法をご紹介したいと思います。
With this AI automation system, you can automatically handle the entire process, from gathering the latest news, writing the posts, to posting them.
このAI自動化システムを活用すれば、最新ニュースの収集から記事の作成、そして投稿まで、全てのプロセスを自動で処理できます。
You can finally achieve your dream of posting daily, without having to worry about what to write.
毎日何を書こうか悩んでいた日々から解放され、夢見ていた1日1投稿を実現できるでしょう。
If you watch till the end, I’ll provide templates, detailed prompt examples, and even show you how I apply this in my work
動画を最後までご覧いただければ、この自動化システムをそのまま適用できるように、テンプレートと詳細な
so that you can implement this automation system right away.
プロンプト例、そして私がどのように実務に応用しているかまで、全てお伝えしますので、
So, please watch till the end.
最後までご覧ください。
Note that while this video focuses on LinkedIn and Twitter, you can also apply this to Instagram or other social media channels.
ちなみに、この動画はリンクトインとツイッターを基準にお話しますが、インスタグラムや他のSNSチャンネルにも十分応用して適用できます。
Now, let's take a look at the final output and see how this automation system works.
それでは、この自動化システムがどのように動作するのか、最終的な成果物を見ながら説明していきます。
This automation system works in three main stages.
この自動化システムは大きく3段階で動作します。
First, we'll use Google Alerts to
まず、1つ目はGoogleアラートを使って、
automatically collect the latest news on your chosen topics from various news sites,
様々なニュースサイトから、皆様が関心のあるテーマの最新ニュースを
and save them to Google Sheets.
Googleスプレッドシートに自動で保存します。
Then, among the collected news, you select the articles you want to post on social media.
そして、収集されたニュースの中から、SNSに投稿したいニュースを選択して、
When you check the checkbox, ChatGPT will automatically turn them into social media posts.
チェックボックスを押すと、ChatGPTがそれを自動的にSNSの記事に変換してくれます。
Lastly, if you like the post that ChatGPT wrote, click the publish button
最後に、ChatGPTが作成した記事が気に入ったら、横の発行ボタンを押して
to automatically post it to your social media accounts.
実際のSNSに自動で投稿することも可能です。
Of course, you can set this up so that the entire process runs fully automatically, without having to check any boxes.
もちろん、このすべてのプロセスをチェックボックスを押す必要もなく、完全に自動で進行するように設定することもできます。
I’ll explain this part in detail later.
この部分については後で詳しく説明する予定です。
Although there's a fully automated method, I recommend using the checkbox method first.
完全自動化する方法もありますが、まずこのチェックボックスを使う方法をお勧めする理由は、
Because it allows for more natural writing.
より自然な文章作成が可能だからです。
By going through this check box process until the prompt is refined,
プロンプトがある程度調整されるまでは、このようにチェックボックスで確認する段階を踏むことで、
you can produce posts that sound like they were written by a person.
人が書いたような文章に仕上げることができます。
We will build this automation system using a site called make.com.
私たちはこの自動化システムをmake.comというサイトを活用して作成する予定です。
If you're new to make.com, you can sign up through the link in the description or the pinned comment.
make.comを初めて使う方は、説明欄または固定コメントからmake.comに登録できますので、参考にしてください。
Let's start with the first step in social media automation: setting up Google Alerts.
それでは、SNS自動化の第一段階であるGoogleアラートの設定から始めましょう。
Through Google Alerts, we can gather news articles daily via RSS.
このGoogleアラートを通じて、RSSで毎日ニュース記事を収集することができます。
Some of you may be unfamiliar with the concept of RSS.
RSSという概念に少し馴染みがない方もいらっしゃるかもしれません。
RSS is a technology that allows users to receive new content
RSSとは、ユーザーがウェブサイトに直接アクセスしなくても、
without having to visit the website directly.
新しいコンテンツを受け取ることができるようにする技術です。
Many news sites and blogs offer their own RSS feeds.
多くのニュースサイトやブログが、独自にRSSフィードを提供しています。
For example, if you subscribe to the Maeil Business Newspaper's RSS feed,
例えば、毎日経済のRSSを購読すれば、
you can receive the latest news alerts without visiting their website.
この毎日経済のサイトにアクセスしなくても、最新のニュースアラートを受け取ることができます。
While you can get RSS feeds from each news site,
それぞれのニュースサイトからRSSを取得することもできますが、
Google Alerts allows you to skip visiting each of those sites.
Googleアラートは、このような各サイトにアクセスする必要がなく、
It’s very useful because you just set keywords here, and it gathers all the news on the topics you're interested in.
ここにキーワードを設定するだけで、関心のあるテーマに関するニュースを全て収集してくれるため、非常に便利です。
Visit the Google Alerts website and search for the keywords you want.
こちらのGoogleアラートのサイトにアクセスして、お好みのキーワードを検索すると、
The latest news related to those keywords will appear.
そのキーワードに関連する最新ニュースが表示されます。
I'll search for "AI".
私はAIで一度検索してみます。
When you search, you'll see a list of AI-related news.
このように検索すると、AI関連のニュースがずらっと表示されます。
If you want to collect this news, click "Create Alert" at the top.
これらのニュースを収集したい場合は、上部のアラートを作成をクリックしてください。
Then, click the pencil icon,
そして、ここの鉛筆部分をクリックして、
change the "Deliver to" option to "RSS feed" and click "Update Alert."
受信場所をRSSフィードに変更し、アラートを更新をクリックします。
An antenna icon will appear next to the AI keyword.
すると、このAIというキーワードの横に、この電波アイコンが表示されます。
Clicking this icon will take you to the RSS news feed address, which is in XML format.
この電波アイコンをクリックすると、XMLで構成されたRSSニュースフィードのアドレスに移動します。
Select the entire address in the address bar, and press Ctrl+C to copy it.
このアドレスバーのアドレスを全選択した後、Ctrl Cを押してコピーしてください。
Now, let's build an automation system using make.com.
いよいよmake.comを活用した自動化システムを構築していきます。
When you log in to make.com, you will see the same screen as mine.
まず、make.comにログインすると、私と同じ画面が表示されると思います。
Click the "Scenarios" button on the left,
左側のシナリオボタンをクリックして、
and click "Create a new scenario" at the top right to create a new scenario.
右上の「新しいシナリオを作成」をクリックして、新しいシナリオを作成してください。
First, let's create a scenario to gather news.
まず、ニュースを収集するシナリオを作成します。
I've already prepared a JSON file to some extent in my YouTube description.
私のYouTubeの説明欄に、ある程度JSONファイルを作成しておきました。
Let’s start with that.
それをベースに始めてみましょう。
First, download the JSON file from the YouTube description.
まず、私のYouTubeの説明欄にあるJSONファイルをダウンロードしてください。
Those of you who have downloaded the file, click the "..." at the bottom of the scenario,
ダウンロードされた方は、こちらのシナリオ下部の「...」をクリックして、
and click "Import Blueprint".
「Blueprintをインポート」をクリックし、
Upload the downloaded file and click "Save."
ダウンロードしたファイルをアップロードして、「保存」をクリックすると、
You'll see a screen like this.
私と同じような画面が表示されるはずです。
Click on the RSS news collection part.
ここで、RSSニュース収集の部分をクリックしてください。
You will see the same options window as mine. Paste the feed address we created earlier into the URL part by pressing Ctrl+V.
私と同じオプションウィンドウが表示されると思いますが、URL部分に、先ほど作成したフィードのアドレスをCtrl Vで貼り付けてください。
This will collect AI news.
これでAIニュースが収集されるはずです。
"Date From" and "Date To" are where you enter the date range for the news to collect.
Date FromとDate Toは、いつからいつまでのニュースを取得するかを入力する欄です。
Currently, it's set to "Now" and "-6", which means it will gather the news from now to 6 days ago.
現在の場合は、「現在」と「-6」になっているので、現在から6日前までのニュースを取得することになっています。
I'll change 6 to 1, so it will only get the news from today until yesterday.
ここでは、6を1に変更して、今日から昨日までのニュースだけを取得してみましょう。
Below, you will see the "Maximum Number of Returned Items" section.
そして、下を見ると、「Maximum Number of Returned Items」と書かれていますが、
This is where you set the number of news to gather at once.
これは一度にいくつのニュースを取得するかを設定する部分です。
It's currently set to gather a maximum of 5 news articles.
今はニュースを5つまで取得するように設定されています。
Keep these settings and click "OK" to save.
この設定のまま、「OK」をクリックして保存します。
Clicking "Run Once" at the bottom will execute this scenario. Let's click it.
下部の「Run Once」ボタンをクリックすると、このシナリオが実行されます。一度クリックしてみましょう。
Click "Run Anyway".
「Run Anyway」をクリックしてください。
Wait a moment after clicking, and a white circle will appear at the top, just like mine.
クリックしてしばらく待つと、私のように上部に白い丸が表示されるはずです。
Click the white circle above the "RSS news collection" section,
この「RSSニュース収集」の上にある白い丸をクリックすると、
and you can see what news has been collected.
実際にどのようなニュースが収集されたかを見ることができます。
You can see that a total of five news articles have been gathered: Bundle 1, Bundle 2, and Bundle 3.
Bundle 1からBundle 2、Bundle 3と、全部で5つのニュースが取得されたことがわかります。
Inside each bundle, you can see the title of the news, an overview of the news,
各バンドルの中を見ると、ニュースのタイトル、そしてニュースの概要、
and the URL has also been collected.
URLも取得されていることがわかります。
Importantly, we only have the news titles and URLs, but not the news content.
ここで重要なのは、今、ニュースのタイトルとURLだけで、ニュースの本文がないことです。
To gather the main content, we need to access the URL and get the actual article content.
本文を取得するには、このURLにアクセスして実際の記事内容を取得する必要がありますが、
However, the problem is that this URL is not the actual article URL.
問題はこのURLが、実際の記事のURLではないということです。
Let me copy it and show you.
コピーして一度お見せします。
If I copy this and paste it into the internet and check the actual destination,
これをコピーしてインターネットの窓に貼り付け、実際に移動するアドレスを確認すると、
you can see that the actual address is this one.
実際のアドレスはこちらであることが確認できます。
To clean up the address and make it a direct URL,
そのため、このアドレスをこのようにきれいなアドレスに整理するために、
I've added 3 modules in advance on make.com.
このmake.comに3つのモジュールを事前に追加しておきました。
Each of these modules act like a filter, cleaning up the complex URL step by step.
それぞれのモジュールがフィルターのように機能し、複雑なURLを段階的にきれいに整理してくれます。
The first module has this pattern inside.
最初のモジュールには、このようなパターンが入っています。
This is a type of rule called a regular expression.
これは正規表現という一種のルールです。
This regular expression rule means that in this URL,
この正規表現のルールは、今のURLから
it will only extract the URL between "URL=" and "&CT."
URL=の次の部分から&CTの間のURLだけを抽出するという意味です。
The second module means it will replace %3D with =.
そして、2つ目のモジュールは、この%3Dを=に置き換えるという意味です。
And the third module means that if there is %3F in the URL, it will replace that with a question mark (?).
そして、3つ目のモジュールは、このURLで%3Fという部分があれば、それを?に置き換えるという意味です。
After these three refining steps,
このように3回の精製作業を経ると、
it will change into the clean article URL that I showed you earlier.
先ほどお見せしたように、きれいな記事URLに変わります。
Let’s click the white module of "URL Refinement 3,"
実際にこのURL精製3の白いモジュールをクリックして、
then click the "Operation" part, and check the output section.
このOperationの部分をクリックして、Outputの部分を確認してみると、
You can see that the real article URL has been extracted cleanly.
このようにきれいに実際の記事URLが抽出されていることがわかります。
Now, let's gather the actual news content using this clean URL.
さあ、このきれいになったURLで、実際のニュース本文を取得してみましょう。
Click the plus button, and search for "http".
横のプラスボタンをクリックして、httpを検索してください。
Then, click "Make a request" and add it.
ここで、「Make a request」をクリックして追加してください。
When you click on the URL part, the results created by the previous modules will appear.
このURLの部分をクリックすると、ここに以前のモジュールが作成した結果がずらっと表示されます。
Think of these boxes marked with different colors as baskets.
この色で表示されたボックスが、一つのバスケットだと考えてください。
Each of these baskets contains the information that we need.
それぞれのバスケットの中に、私たちが必要な情報が入っているんです。
The information that we need to put here,
今、ここに入れるべき情報は、
is the clean URL that was filtered by URL Refinement 3.
URL精製3番のモジュールを通してきれいにフィルターされたURLですよね。
If you look under URL Refinement 3,
そのため、このURL精製3の下を見ると、
you will see a preview of what is contained in that basket.
このバスケットの中に何が入っているか、このようにプレビューで表示されます。
Because it contains the clean URL,
ここにきれいに整えられたURLが入っているので、
click the text basket from URL Refinement 3 to add it.
このURL精製3番のテキストバスケットをクリックして、このように追加すれば良いでしょう。
The method will remain as "get" in its current state, which means to get or gather the news.
メソッドは現在の状態のまま、getにしておくと、ニュースをget、つまり取得するという意味になります。
Here’s a tip only the pros know.
ここで、ベテランだけが知っている裏技を一つお教えします。
Most sites block scraping of their content
ほとんどのサイトは、自社のサイトから情報をスクレイピングされるのを防ぐために、
by checking the headers. If it looks like a bot is scraping, they'll block it.
このヘッダーを検査して、ロボットがスクレイピングしているようだと遮断するんです。
So, we'll create fake headers to make the site think we're real people.
そこで、私たちはこのサイトが本物の人間だと錯覚するように、偽のヘッダーを作成します。
In the header section, click "add header."
ヘッダー部分で、このように「ヘッダーを追加」をクリックして、
Add "cookie" to the name section.
name部分にcookieを追加してください。
Click it again,
もう一度クリックして、
and type "accept."
「accept」と入力してください。
Click it once more, and this time, type "accept"
そして、もう一度クリックして、今度は「accept」
-Encoding" and add it.
-Encoding」と入力して、
Add another one and type "User-Agent."
もう一度追加して、「User-Agent」と追加します。
This will allow us to scrape news from website URLs.
これで、ウェブサイトのURLからニュースをスクレイピングできるようになります。
Let's test to see if it scrapes well.
実際にうまくスクレイピングできるかテストしてみましょう。
Click OK.
「OK」をクリックしてください。
Let's click run once to test it.
下の「Run Once」をクリックしてテストしてみましょう。
A white circle will appear above the http module.
すると、このようにhttpモジュールの上に白い丸が表示され、
If you click it, you can see that it says 5 news articles and 5 results have been executed.
クリックすると、5つのニュース、5つの結果が実行されたと表示されることがわかります。
Click any operation, and
このうち、どれかのoperationをクリックすると、
you can see that these values were input and these values were output.
inputとしてこのような値が入り、このような値が出力されたと表示されることがわかります。
If you click the data under the bundle in the output,
ここで、outputの下にあるバンドルの下にあるデータをクリックすると、
you can see the entire HTML of the corresponding web page, including the news article, has been scraped.
このように、該当のウェブページにあるニュース、記事を含むhtml全体がスクレイピングされたことがわかります。
But what we really need is not this entire HTML code, but the content of the news.
しかし、私たちにとって本当に必要なのは、このhtmlコード全体ではなく、ニュースの内容ですよね。
So, we need to extract only the actual text from this HTML code.
そこで、このhtmlコードから実際のテキストだけを抽出する必要があります。
Let’s add a new module for this.
このために、新しいモジュールを追加します。
Click the plus button, and search for "Text parser".
プラスボタンをクリックし、「Text parser」を検索してください。
When you click on Text parser, you'll see an "html to text" module.
この「Text parser」をクリックすると、「html to text」というモジュールがあります。
Click on it. If you insert the html to be converted in the "html" section, it will convert it into text format.
これを選択して、このhtmlの欄に変換したいhtmlを入れると、それをテキスト形式に変換してくれます。
Click the empty space, and the results from previous modules will appear, like before.
ここの空白をクリックすると、先ほどのように、以前のモジュールの結果の値がずらっと表示されます。
What we need is the results from this http module, this data value.
ここで、私たちに必要なのは、このhttpモジュールの結果の値である、このデータの値を入れることです。
Click data to add it, and then click "OK".
データボタンをクリックして入れて、「OK」をクリックします。
Let's run it once.
一度実行してみます。
Click "Run Anyway."
「Run Anyway」をクリックしてください。
Wait a moment, and the http module will execute. Then, 5 results will appear in the Text parser.
少し待つと、このようにhttpモジュールが実行され、この「Text parser」に5つの結果が生成されます。
Click on it. Inside the output, in the text section,
クリックすると、このOutputの中のテキスト欄を見ると、
you can see that only the text area with the html has been removed.
htmlが削除されたテキスト領域だけが残っていることがわかります。
However, if you look at the extracted news in detail,
しかし、抽出されたニュースを詳しく見ると、
what we want is the actual content, but not only the main content.
ここで私たちが欲しいのは、この実際の本文ですが、本文だけでなく、
You can see that it also includes things like sharing options and website menu sections.
このように共有やウェブサイトのメニュー部分など、このような部分もすべて一緒に含まれていることがわかります。
Since we only want the main text, let's extract only that part cleanly.
ここで、私たちが必要なのは、このテキスト本文の部分だけなので、これだけをきれいに抽出してみましょう。
Before that, let’s change the names of the added modules to something easier to understand.
その前に、追加したモジュールの名前も、もう少しわかりやすく変更しておきます。
Right-click on the http module and click "rename".
このhttpモジュールで右クリックして、
I'll change it to "Extract News Data".
「rename」をクリックして「ニュースデータ抽出」に変更しましょう。
And also, rename the "Text parser" and change it to
そして、「Text parser」も「rename」をクリックして、これは
"Convert HTML to Text".
「htmlをテキストに変換」に変更します。
Next, click the plus button beside the module to add a new module.
次に、このモジュールの横にあるプラスボタンをクリックして、新しいモジュールを追加します。
Click "Open AI," and click "Create a Completion."
「Open AI」をクリックし、ここで「Create a compilation」をクリックしてください。
For those who are connecting for the first time, you won't see the connection like me but a button that you can click.
初めてアクセスする方は、私のように接続されているのではなく、ここにボタン形式で表示されるはずです。
The method for connecting is not difficult. I'll leave it in detail in the description.
接続方法は難しくないので、説明欄に詳しく残しておきます。
Follow that guide to connect, and you'll see the same window as me.
それを使って接続を進めていただければ、私と同じウィンドウが表示されます。
Now, let’s configure settings to cleanly extract the main body of the news.
さあ、ニュース本文をきれいに抽出するための設定をしてみましょう。
In the options section, select GPT-3.5 for the model.
オプション部分のモデルで、GPT-3.5を選択します。
I’ll select 3.5 turbo 0125.
3.5ターボ0125を選択します。
If you set the model to GPT-4o, the accuracy will improve,
モデルをGPT-4oにすると、精度は上がりますが、
but the amount of text inside is very large as you saw earlier.
今ここに入っているテキストの量が、先ほどご覧いただいたように非常に多いですよね。
So, if you use GPT-4o, the cost will be too high.
そのため、GPT-4oにすると、費用が高くなりすぎてしまうので、
So, I’ll use the cheaper GPT-3.5 for this.
ここでは安いGPT-3.5を使います。
Next, add a message below the Message, and set the role to "user."
そして、メッセージの下にある「メッセージを追加」をクリックして、役割を「ユーザー」に設定してください。
Then, write this in the text content.
テキストコンテンツに、このように書いてください。
"Remove all parts of this document that are not related to the news."
「この文書から、このニュースと関係のない部分をすべて削除して。」
"Only the news title and the news content should remain."
「ニュースのタイトルとニュースの本文だけを残して。」
#Document
#文書
And to let ChatGPT know what the topic of this news is, I will add it here.
このようにして、ChatGPTにこのニュースのテーマが何かを知らせるために、ここに追加します。
Put parentheses next to the news,
ニュースの横に括弧をつけた後、
and add the title of the news from the RSS collection module,
この中に、ニュースのタイトルが入っているこのRSS収集モジュール下部の
by clicking the title section.
「タイトル」部分をクリックして追加します。
And also, next to the document, add the news content that we’ll extract,
そして、文書の横にも、私たちが抽出するニュースの内容が入っている
by clicking the text in the html to text conversion module.
このhtmlテキスト変換モジュールの中にあるテキストをクリックして追加します。
Then, turn on "Show Advanced Settings" below,
そして、この下にある「Show advanced settings」をオンにして、
open the advanced menu, and lower the temperature to about 0.2.
詳細メニューを開き、ここの温度を0.2程度に下げます。
The closer this temperature value is to 1, the more creative the response will be.
この温度の値が1に近いほど、創造的な回答が得られますが、
But since we don't need a creative response at this time, set it to around 0.2, which is close to 0.
今回はそれほど創造的な回答が必要なわけではないので、0に近い0.2程度に設定します。
"Max completion token" is where you set the length of the response,
そして、Max completion tokenは、回答の長さを設定するものですが、
but I will enter 0 here to have no limitations to the length of the response.
ここでは回答の長さに制限を設けないために、0を入力します。
Click "OK," and click "Run Once" again to execute it.
「OK」をクリックした後、もう一度「Run Once」をクリックして実行してみましょう。
Since it costs a lot, let's run only the first one and click stop.
費用がかかるため、最初のものだけ実行し、「停止」をクリックします。
After it executes, click this white bubble at the top of the Open AI
このように実行された後、「Open AI」上部のこの
to check the result.
白い風船をクリックして、結果の値を確認すると、
You can see that the actual news content has been extracted in the result section.
このResultの中に、実際のニュース本文がこのように抽出されていることがわかります。
Note that, right now, I’m using 3.5-0125, which is the cheapest option.
ちなみに、今は3.5、0125という一番費用の安いもので実行しているので、
So, the content extraction isn't very accurate.
今、本文の抽出が非常に正確に行われているわけではありません。
The more expensive the model you use, the more accurate the results will be.
もう少し高いモデルを使うほど、この結果の値も非常に正確に出力されるので、
Please consider the cost when you’re setting up your configuration.
その点は価格の部分を考慮して設定してください。
Now that the news content has been extracted successfully, let's save this content in Google Sheets.
このようにニュース本文がうまく出力されたので、この本文をGoogleスプレッドシートに保存します。
First, let's create a Google Sheet.
まず、Googleスプレッドシートを作成しましょう。
Go to the Google Spreadsheets site, create a blank spreadsheet,
Googleスプレッドシートのサイトにアクセスして、空白のスプレッドシートをクリックして作成した後、
and name it "News Scrap". Add headers at the top: "Title", "Original URL",
「ニューススクラップ」という名前をつけて、一番上の行に「タイトル」「原文URL」
and "Date Posted".
「作成日」とヘッダーを追加します。
Go back to make.com.
再びmake.comに戻り、
Click the plus button to the right of the last Open AI module, and click on the Google Sheets,
この最後のOpen AIモジュールの右側にあるプラスボタンをクリックして、このGoogleスプレッドシートをクリックします。
and select "Add a row".
そして、「行を追加」を選択してください。
I've already linked Google Sheets to my account, so it appears like this.
私はすでにGoogleスプレッドシートと連携しているので、このように表示されていますが、
But for you, a button will appear.
皆さんにはボタンが表示されると思います。
Click that button and log in to connect.
それをクリックしてログインすると接続されます。
After connecting, click the button under Spreadsheet ID,
接続した後、このスプレッドシートIDの下にあるボタンをクリックして、
search for the News Scrap that we created earlier, and add it.
先ほど作成したニューススクラップを検索して追加します。
And for the sheet name, use sheet1. Since we added headers earlier,
そして、シート名はsheet1、先ほどヘッダーを作成したので、
set the "Headers" option to yes.
ヘッダーの有無は「はい」にしてください。
In the "Values" section, you can put the data that you want to input into Google Sheets.
そして、この「値」という部分が、Googleスプレッドシートに入力するデータを入力する部分です。
Since we need to put the news title in the title column, click on the title under the RSS News Collection module,
タイトル列に、ニュースのタイトルを入力する必要があるので、このポップアップウィンドウで、
in this pop-up window, and add it.
このRSSニュース収集モジュールの下にある「title」をクリックして入力します。
Next, we need to add the original news article to the "Original" section.
次に、原文の部分には、ニュース記事の原文を入力する必要があるので、
In this pop-up window, we extracted the original news content using the Open AI module,
このポップアップウィンドウで、Open AIモジュールを使って抽出したニュースの原文を追加します。
so add the result value.
この「result」の値を入力すればOKです。
And for the URL section,
そして、URL欄には、
add the text result from the URL Refinement 3 module, which is the cleaned-up version of the URL.
このURL精製3番のモジュールを通過して、きれいに整理されたURLの結果の値テキストを入力します。
For the "Date Posted" section, select and add the date created from the RSS news collection module.
そして、作成日の部分には、このRSSニュース収集モジュール下部にある、「date created」
Choose the created date and add it.
作成された日付を選択して入力すればOKです。
Click "OK".
「OK」をクリックしてください。
Let’s click Run Once to see if it works.
実際にうまく動作するか、「Run Once」をクリックしてみましょう。
Let’s wait for it to finish.
クリックして実行されるまで、少し待ってみましょう。
Sometimes, errors can occur while it’s executing.
このように実行中に、エラーが表示されることがあります。
The reason for this error is because it’s exceeding the maximum token count of GPT 3.5.
今このエラーが表示された理由は、GPT3.5の最大トークン数を超えたためです。
In this case, right click and
このような場合は、ここで右クリックして、
add an error handler.
「エラーハンドラーを追加」をクリックしてください。
You can specify how to handle the error.
このエラーが発生した場合にどのように処理するかを記述することができます。
If you select "ignore" in the error handler module,
このエラーハンドラーモジュールの中から「ignore」を選択すると、
it will ignore the error and continue execution.
そのエラーを無視して実行を継続します。
It says that the results for four of the news articles have been executed. Let’s check the "News Scrap" Google Sheet.
4つまでは、結果の値がすべて実行されたと表示されますが、ニューススクラップのGoogleシートに移動してみましょう。
You can see that these four news articles have been successfully scraped.
すると、このように4つのニュースがうまくスクラップされていることがわかります。
Now, since we added the error handler, let's run it again and check if it executes properly.
さて、エラーハンドラーを追加したので、もう一度実行して、うまく実行されるかどうか確認してみましょう。
Click "Run Once" and it’s executing.
「Run Once」をクリックすると、このように実行されています。
The first one executed, and the second one too.
1回目の実行が完了し、2回目の実行も完了しました。
It says the third one has been completed.
3回目の実行が完了したと表示されています。
The fourth one has been processed as well.
4回目もこのようにうまく処理され、
It has ignored one error and has saved the other four to the "News Scrap" sheet.
エラーが発生した1件は無視し、残りの4件はこのニューススクラップにうまく保存されていることがわかります。
So far, we’ve built a flow that gathers news.
このように、ニュースを収集するフローを作成しました。
We're done after one more modification.
ここから、もう一つだけ修正すれば完了です。
That is, the execution interval of this scenario.
それは、このシナリオの実行間隔です。
Click the clock icon on the left of the first module.
ここの最初のモジュールの左側にある時計アイコンをクリックして、
You can set the execution interval of the scenario here.
ここでシナリオの実行間隔を設定することができます。
The default is 15 minutes, as you can see.
デフォルト値は、ご覧のとおり15分になっています。
You can change this execution interval to what you want.
ここで、実行間隔を希望の間隔に変更できます。
If you want to collect news every morning,
毎朝ニュースを収集したい場合は、
click below Run Scenario, change the execution interval to "Every Day",
ここにある「シナリオを実行」の下をクリックして、実行間隔を「Every Day」に変更し、
and change the time to the time you want and click OK.
時間を...希望の時間に変更した後、「OK」をクリックします。
Then, it will ask if you want to activate the scenario.
すると、「シナリオを有効にしますか？」と表示されます。
Click "Activate Scenario" to activate it.
「有効にする」つまり「Activate Scenario」をクリックすると、
This part will be turned on, and it’s set up to run every day at 4:06 PM.
この部分がオンになり、毎日午後4時6分に実行するように設定が完了します。
Now, let's build an automated social media publishing system using the collected news.
さあ、この収集したニュースをもとに、SNS自動発行システムを作っていきましょう。
First, let’s add a header “Convert to Social Media Post” in the Google Sheet.
まず、Googleスプレッドシートに「SNS記事に変換」というヘッダーを追加します。
And add check boxes below it.
そして、その下にチェックボックスを追加します。
Next to it, type LinkedIn and Twitter.
そして、この横に「リンクトイン」「ツイッター」と続けて記述します。
When the Convert to Social Media Post checkbox is checked, a LinkedIn post and a Twitter post will be created next to it.
この「SNS記事に変換」のチェックボックスがチェックされたら、横にリンクトイン用の記事とツイッター用の記事が生成されるようにします。
And type "Publish" next to it.
そして、横に「発行」と記述します。
Add checkboxes here as well.
ここにもチェックボックスを追加します。
If this checkbox is checked, the posts created here will be immediately published.
このチェックボックスにチェックが入ると、ここに作成された記事がすぐに発行されるようにします。
First, we need to make sure Make can detect when this checkbox is checked.
まず、このチェックボックスにチェックが入ったときに、Makeで感知できるようにする必要があります。
The connection that allows this is called a webhook.
その役割を果たす連結点をウェブフックといいます。
A webhook can be set up using the Google Sheets extension of make.com.
ウェブフックは、make.comのGoogleスプレッドシート拡張機能を利用すれば設定できます。
In the "Extensions" menu, click "Add-ons", and then "Get add-ons".
拡張機能メニューから「アドオン」、「アドオンを取得」をクリックしてください。
Search for "make" here,
ここで「make」を検索すると、
and the extension will appear.
このように拡張機能が表示されます。
I already have it installed, so it says "Uninstall".
私はすでにインストールされているので「削除」と表示されますが、
But for you, it will say "Install". Click it to install.
皆さんには「インストール」と表示されると思います。「インストール」をクリックしてインストールを進めてください。
Then, go back to make.com, and click "Create a new scenario" to create a new scenario.
そして、make.comに戻り、再び「新しいシナリオを作成」をクリックして新しいシナリオを作成してください。
Click the Google Sheet and the "Watch changes" module and add it.
ここで、Googleスプレッドシート、「変更を監視」モジュールをクリックして追加してください。
When the webhook section appears, click "Add" next to it to create a new webhook.
このウェブフックの部分が表示されたら、横の「追加」をクリックして新しいウェブフックを作成します。
The Webhook URL will appear.
すると、このようにウェブフックURLが表示されます。
Click "Copy Address" to copy it, and go back to Google Sheets.
これを「アドレスをコピー」をクリックしてコピーし、再びGoogleスプレッドシートに戻って、
Click "Extensions", "Make for Google Sheets", and then "Settings" to bring up the sidebar.
「拡張機能」、「make for Google sheets」、「設定」をクリックして、横のサイドバーを表示します。
There's a section where you can enter the Webhook URL.
すると、ここにウェブフックURLを入力する欄があります。
Paste it here using Ctrl+V, and click save to connect.
ここにCtrl vで貼り付けて「保存」をクリックすると接続されます。
It will say that the settings have been saved.
このように設定が完了したと表示されます。
Go back to the make scenario and click "OK".
makeシナリオに戻って「OK」をクリックします。
To test, click Run Once at the bottom.
テストのために、下の「Run Once」をクリックします。
The circle will spin, and it will say that it’s detecting the Google Sheet.
すると、このように丸が回転して、Googleスプレッドシートを感知していると表示されます。
In this state, if you check a checkbox in the Google Sheet,
この状態で、Googleスプレッドシートでチェックボックスをこのようにチェックすると、
it will say it has been detected, and the results will appear.
このように感知されたと表示され、結果の値が表示されます。
If you check the content in the output bundle,
ここで、「Output」バンドルの中身を確認すると、
the old value is false, which means the checkbox was unchecked,
「old value」は「false」つまりチェックボックスがチェックされていなかったのですが、
and the current value is true, which means the make has successfully detected the change in the checkbox.
今の「value」は「true」でチェックボックスの変更をmakeがうまく感知していることがわかります。
Click the range section to open it,
そして、「range」部分をクリックして開くと、
you can see that it says that the detection occurred on the second row and fifth column.
この感知された事項が2行目と5列目で感知されたと表示されます。
If you check the location of the checkbox we checked, you can see it is on the second row and the fifth column.
実際に私たちがチェックしたこのチェックボックスの位置を見ると、2行目と5列目で間違いないですよね？
You can see that it has been detected successfully.
このように、うまく感知していることが確認できます。
Now that we’ve verified that the webhook is working correctly, let’s continue.
ウェブフックが正常に動作することを確認したので、引き続き作成してみましょう。
Click the plus button next to the module, and add "Router" which is in "Flow control".
モジュールの横のプラスボタンをクリックして、「フロー制御」の中にある「ルーター」を追加してください。
If you add it, you'll see that it divides into two paths.
追加すると、このように道が2つに分かれます。
The top path will be the flow for when the "Convert to Social Media Post" checkbox is checked, where the post will be written,
上側はSNS記事変換チェックボックスをチェックすると記事が書かれるフロー、
and the bottom path will be the flow for when the Publish checkbox is checked, where the post will be published.
下側は発行チェックボックスをチェックすると記事が発行されるフローを作成します。
Right click on the top line, and click "Set up a filter" to open the filter window.
この上側の線の上で右クリックし、「フィルター設定」をクリックして、このフィルターウィンドウを表示してください。
Since this path should be executed when the "Convert to Social Media Post" checkbox is checked,
SNS記事変換チェックボックスをクリックしたときに、ここが実行される必要があるので、
create a rule where the old value is false, and the current value is true.
古い値が「false」で、ここの値が「true」というルールを作成します。
Then, add another "and rule", and click "Column start".
そして、「end」をもう一つ追加して、「Column start」をクリックします。
The checkbox that we're trying to configure is in the first, second, third, fourth, and fifth column.
今、設定しようとしているチェックボックスの位置は、1、2、3、4、5番目の列ですよね？
So, put 5 in the column start section.
そのため、「Column start」部分に5を入力し、
Then, add another "and rule", and add 5 in the column end section as well.
もう一つ「end」を追加して、「Column end」も同じく5と追加します。
Click "OK".
「OK」をクリックしてください。
With this, this flow will only be executed when the "Convert to Social Media Post" checkbox is checked.
これで、SNS記事変換チェックボックスにチェックを入れた時だけ、このフローが実行されるようになります。
Next, click the plus button and select "Open AI Create a Completion".
その後、この後ろにプラスボタンをクリックして、「Open AI Create a Completion」を選択します。
I'll select the GPT-4o Mini for the model.
モデルをGPT-4o Miniに選択します。
Click "Add Message", and set the role to "User".
そして、「メッセージを追加」をクリックして、役割を「ユーザー」に設定します。
In the Text content section, copy and paste the prompt from the YouTube description.
このテキストコンテンツの部分に、YouTubeの説明欄にあるプロンプトをコピーして貼り付けます。
This prompt is to ask ChatGPT, acting as a marketer, to create good LinkedIn and Twitter posts.
このプロンプトは、ChatGPTにマーケターの役割を担わせ、リンクトインの記事とツイッターの記事をうまく書いてくれるように依頼するものです。
When we ask ChatGPT, we need to provide the news content to be converted into social media posts.
ChatGPTに依頼する際、SNS記事に変換する記事の原文を入力する必要があるので、
So, we'll add the original news content after the "Read and Analyze" section.
ここにある「読んで分析してください。」という次の部分に記事の原文を追加します。
If we check where the original news content is in Google Sheet, we can see that it’s in the second column.
このGoogleスプレッドシートで、記事の原文がどこにあるかを確認すると、2列目にあることがわかります。
So, in this pop-up window, click the B column, which is the second column in "Row Value", and add it.
そのため、このポップアップウィンドウで、「Row Value」の中にある2列目のB列をクリックして追加します。
Also, to display the source, we'll also add the URL next to the original link.
そして、出所も一緒に表記するために、URLもこの原文リンクの横の部分に追加します。
If we check where the URL is in the Google Sheet again, we can see it is in the third column.
Googleスプレッドシートで、URLがどこにあるかを確認すると、3列目にあることがわかります。
So, in the prompt section, enter the third column, which is the C column, in this pop-up window.
そのため、ここのプロンプト部分で、ポップアップウィンドウから3列目のC列を入力します。
Then, scroll down and set the "Max Tokens" to about 1000.
そして、下にスクロールして、このMax Tokensを1000程度に設定します。
Then, turn on "Show Advanced Settings" below.
そして、この下にある「Show Advanced Settings」をオンにした後、
And set the temperature to about 0.32.
この温度を0.32程度に設定します。
Leave the rest as the default, and click OK.
残りはデフォルト値のままにして、「OK」をクリックしてください。
Click "Run Once" to test it.
「Run Once」をクリックしてテストしてみましょう。
Go to the Google Sheet,
Googleシートに移動した後、
check the checkbox next to the news you want to post, and go back to the Make scenario.
文章を書きたいニュースの横のチェックボックスをオンにして、再びMakeシナリオに戻ると、
You can see that it has detected the change, and the input was entered into ChatGPT which is writing the post.
このように変化を感知し、ChatGPTにInputが入り、このように文章を書いてくれることがわかります。
If you check the result value,
結果の値を確認すると、
in the "Output" section, click "Result", and you can see that a LinkedIn post,
このOutputの部分のResultをクリックすると、このようにリンクトインの記事と
and a Twitter post were created.
ツイッターの記事がうまく書かれていることが確認できます。
We will add the LinkedIn post to the LinkedIn column in the Google Sheet.
ここで、リンクトインの記事部分は、Googleスプレッドシートのリンクトインの列に
And we will add the Twitter post to the Twitter column in the Google Sheet.
そして、ツイッター部分は、このGoogleスプレッドシートのツイッターの列部分に追加します。
Since the two posts are combined into one, we will use a tool called a regular expression to separate them.
今は、2つの記事が一つにまとまっているので、分離するために正規表現というツールを使用します。
As mentioned earlier, a regular expression is
正規表現は先ほども述べたように、
a type of formula that extracts the parts of the text that we want.
テキストから、私たちが欲しい部分だけを抽出する一種の数式だと考えてください。
Click the plus button next to Open AI,
ここにあるOpen AIの横のプラスボタンをクリックして、
and select "Match Pattern" under "Text parser."
Text parserの下にある「一致パターン」を選択します。
Copy and paste the regular expression pattern that I've uploaded in the pinned comment, here.
そしてここに、私がYouTubeの固定コメントに掲載しておいた正規表現パターンをコピーして貼り付けます。
And change "Global match" to "Yes".
そして、「グローバルマッチ」のみ「はい」に変更すると、
It will search the text from beginning to the end, and find all values that match this pattern.
テキストを最初から最後まで検索し、このパターンと一致するすべての値を探してくれます。
Then, in the "Text" section, add the "Result" value that ChatGPT created earlier.
そして、「テキスト」の部分に、先ほどChatGPTが作成した「Result」の結果の値を入力します。
Click OK, and click Run Once again to test it.
「OK」をクリックし、もう一度テストのために「Run Once」をクリックします。
Click "Run Anyway".
「Run Anyway」をクリックしてください。
Then go back to the Google Sheet, and check the checkboxes next to the news that you want to write about.
そしてGoogleスプレッドシートに戻り、文章を書きたいニュースの横の部分にチェックボックスを入れます。
When you come back here, you can see that Open AI has created the post,
そして、このように戻ってくると、Open AIが文章を作成し、
and the text parser has separated the posts into two parts,
この文章をText parserが2つに分割して、このように
a LinkedIn post and a Twitter post.
リンクトインの記事とツイッターの記事に分離してくれたことが確認できます。
Now, let's save these posts into the Google Sheet.
次に、これらの記事をGoogleスプレッドシートに保存します。
Click the plus button next to the Text parser, and select "Flow Control".
「Text parser」の横にあるプラスボタンをクリックし、「フロー制御」を選択します。
We will add a filter so that the LinkedIn post is saved in the upper path, and the Twitter post is saved in the bottom path.
上側にはリンクトインの投稿、下側にはツイッターの投稿が保存されるようにフィルターをかけます。
If you look at the results from this text parser,
先ほどのこの「Text parser」の結果を見ると、
you can see that the first LinkedIn post says "i = 1", and the second Twitter post says "i = 2".
最初のリンクトインの記事は、iが1と表示され、2番目のツイッターの記事はiが2と表示されています。
We will use this to set the filter.
これを基準にフィルターをかけます。
Click the first line, turn on the filter, click "i" in the pop-up window, and type 1.
ここの最初の線をクリックしてフィルターをオンにし、ポップアップから「i」をクリックして「1」と入力します。
Click "OK".
「OK」をクリックしてください。
This will make only the first post, which is the LinkedIn post, pass through this path.
これで、最初の記事であるリンクトインの記事だけがこちらを通るようになります。
Then, click the plus button, and this time select Google Sheets,
そして、プラスボタンをクリックし、今度はGoogleスプレッドシート、
then "Update a row". For the "Spreadsheet ID", select the "News Scrap" sheet that we created earlier.
「行を更新」を選択し、このスプレッドシートIDに、先ほど作成した
Select the "News Scrap" sheet.
「ニューススクラップ」シートを選択し、
"Sheet Name": Sheet1, and the "Row number" should be selected as "Row End".
「シート名」：sheet1、そして「行番号」はここで「row end」を選択します。
In the "Values" section, since we're saving the LinkedIn post, add
そして、「値」の部分に、今、リンクトインの記事を保存しているので、このリンクトイン列に
this "fallback match" to the LinkedIn column.
この「fallback match」の部分を入力すればOKです。
Click "OK".
「OK」をクリックしてください。
Similarly, for the second path, enter the "i" and put 2 for its value, and then click "OK".
2つ目も同様にフィルターを「i」で入力し、そして、値は「2」と入力した後、「OK」をクリックします。
Add "Google Sheets update a row" and
同じように、Googleスプレッドシートの「行を更新」を追加し、
set the other options the same as above.
残りのオプションは上のものと全く同じに設定します。
In the "Values" section, instead of the LinkedIn section, add the "fallback match" to the Twitter section.
そして、「値」の部分だけ、リンクトインの部分ではなくツイッターの部分に「fallback match」を入力すればOKです。
To check if it's working correctly again, click "Run Once" and check the checkbox in the Google Sheet.
もう一度、正常に動作するかどうか確認するために、「Run Once」をクリックして、Googleスプレッドシートでチェックボックスをオンにします。
It’s detecting the change, ChatGPT is writing the post, and it says that the Google Sheet has been executed.
すると、このように感知され、ChatGPTが記事を作成して、Googleスプレッドシートが実行されたと表示されます。
If you go to the sheet, you can see that the LinkedIn post and the Twitter post have been created successfully.
シートに移動すると、このようにリンクトインの記事とツイッターの記事がうまく生成されていることが確認できます。
Now that we’ve finished the automatic post creation, let's create the automatic post publishing section.
記事の自動生成部分が完成したので、記事の自動発行部分も作成してみましょう。
Create a filter in the line section below the first Router.
この最初のルーターの下の線部分にフィルターを作成します。
This time, the path needs to be executed when the "Publish" checkbox is checked.
今回は、発行チェックボックスにチェックを入れたときに、ここが実行される必要があるため、
Set "Column start" to the 8th column, where the "Publish" checkbox is located.
「Column start」を発行チェックボックスがある列である8列目に入力します。
Add an "and rule", and set the "Column end" to the 8th column as well.
そして、「end rule」を追加した後、「Column end」も8番目
Then, set the "Old value" to false and the "Value" to true.
そして、「Old value」が「False」で、「value」の値が「True」の場合に設定します。
Click the plus button, and add a "Router" from "Flow control".
そして、ここのプラスボタンをクリックして、「フロー制御」の「ルーター」を追加してください。
Click the first plus button, search for "LinkedIn,"
そして、最初のプラスボタンをクリックして「リンクトイン」を検索し、
and click "Create a user text post" to add it.
ここで「Create a user text post」をクリックして追加します。
I’ve already connected it to my account, so it appears like this, but you can click the button to connect your account.
私は事前に接続しているので、このように表示されますが、皆さんはここにあるボタンをクリックして接続を進めてください。
In the content section, add the LinkedIn post.
そして、「コンテンツ」の部分にリンクトインの投稿記事を入力します。
In the Google Sheet, the LinkedIn post is located in the F column,
Googleスプレッドシートで、リンクトインの投稿が入っている列であるF列を選択すれば良いので、
so add the F column in "Row Value".
この「row value」の中にあるF列を入力します。
Click "OK," and the setting is finished.
「OK」をクリックすると、設定は完了です。
Similarly, search for "X" or "Twitter" and click "Create a post" in X.
この部分も同様にX、つまりツイッターを検索して、このXの中にある「Create post」をクリックします。
I’ve already connected it to my account, so it appears like this.
私は事前に連携しているので、このように表示されますが、
For Twitter, you need to get the API application approved before you can post on Make.
ツイッターの場合は、事前にAPI申請が承認されないと、Makeでこのように投稿することはできません。
It’s a hassle, but applying for the API isn’t difficult. I'll leave a link for the application method.
面倒ではありますが、このAPI申請は難しくないので、この申請方法をリンクで残しておきます。
Refer to that link and finish connecting your Twitter account. In this text content section,
それを参考にして、ツイッターの連携を完了してから、このテキストコンテンツの部分に、
add the G column, which contains the Twitter content.
ツイッターの内容が入っているこのG列を入力します。
Click the G column in "Row Values," add it and click "OK" to finish setting it up.
「row values」の中にあるG列をクリックして入力し、「OK」をクリックすると設定は完了です。
Now, let's test the automatic publishing.
では、自動発行をテストしてみましょう。
Click "Run Once", then click "Way for New Data".
「Run Once」をクリックして「Way for New Data」をクリックした後、
In the Google Sheet, click the "Publish" checkbox next to the post you want to publish.
Googleスプレッドシートで、発行したい記事の横の発行チェックボックスをオンにして、
If you go back to the Make scenario, you can see that it’s been executed.
Makeシナリオに戻ると、このように実行されていることがわかります。
Let’s go to LinkedIn and check.
実際にリンクトインにアクセスして確認してみましょう。
You can see that the LinkedIn post has been successfully posted.
このようにリンクトインの記事がうまく投稿されていることが確認できます。
You can also see that the Twitter post has been created successfully.
ツイッターもこのように記事がうまく生成されていることが確認できます。
Now, in the scheduling section below,
次に、この下のスケジューリング部分にある、
turn on "Immediately as Data Arrives" to have it always detect the Google Sheet. This will finish the system settings.
このGoogleスプレッドシートを常に感知するように、「Immediately as Data Arrives」をオンにするとシステム設定が完了します。
To delete the existing data, click "Delete Old Data" and then "Delete", then the settings are complete.
既存のデータを削除するために、「Delete Old Data」、「Delete」をクリックすると設定が完了します。
From now on, with just one click of a checkbox,
これからは、チェックボックスを一つクリックするだけで、
AI will write and publish the post for you, and you can make your dream of daily posting a reality.
AIが自動的に文章を作成し、発行までしてくれるので、夢に描いていた1日1投稿も現実のものにすることができるでしょう。
I'm also using this system to automatically collect the latest news in my areas of interest and post them on social media.
ちなみに、私はこのシステムで、自分の関心分野の最新ニュースを自動で収集し、SNSに投稿しています。
I highly recommend this system, especially to those who want to build their personal brand through various social media channels.
特に、複数のSNSを通じてセルフブランディングをしようとしている方には、強くお勧めします。
Some of you may be worried if the posts written by AI will be good enough.
そして、AIが書いた記事は大丈夫なのかと心配する人もいるかと思います。
Since all posts in this system are saved in the Google Sheet first, you can check and modify them before publishing.
このシステムは、すべての記事がまずGoogleスプレッドシートに保存されるため、発行前に確認して修正できます。
You can refine the prompts while looking at the results.
結果を見ながらプロンプトを少しずつ改善し、
If you’re satisfied with the quality of the generated posts, you can also automate the publishing step.
この生成された記事の品質が十分に満足できるようになったら、この発行段階も自動化できます。
The method is simple.
方法は簡単です。
In the make scenario, just attach the LinkedIn and X modules to the lower part of the update module.
このMakeシナリオで、この発行部分のリンクトインとXモジュールを、この更新モジュールの下に取り付ければOKです。
Then, you can upgrade to a one-step automation where the post creation and publishing are all handled at once.
そうすると、ニュースを選択するだけで、記事作成から発行まで一度に処理されるワンステップ自動化にアップグレードできます。
And, for those of you who followed along till the end, I’m giving away this system for free
そして、ここまでご覧いただいた方のために、このシステムをすぐに活用できるように、
as a make.com scenario template and prompt examples, so that you can utilize it immediately.
make.comシナリオテンプレートとプロンプト例をすべて無料で提供しています。
If you need them, you can download them by joining my group chat or subscribing to my newsletter, through the pinned comment.
必要な方は、固定コメントから私のグループチャットコミュニティまたはニュースレターを購読していただければ、すぐにダウンロードできますので、参考にしてください。
You can also ask questions and get answers on various AI usage tips in the group chat.
グループチャットでは、様々なAI活用チップに関する質問や回答を交換することもできるので、
So, if you are struggling with building this type of automation system, please feel free to join.
このような自動化システムの構築に困難を感じている方も、お気軽にご参加いただければと思います。
Today, I explained how to build a system that automates social media posting using make.com.
今日はこのように、make.comを活用してSNS投稿を自動化するシステムを構築する方法について説明しました。
If you want to see more AI usage tips, please subscribe and turn on notifications.
より多くのAI活用チップについて知りたい場合は、チャンネル登録と通知設定をお願いします。
I'll be back with more helpful information in the next video.
次の動画では、さらに有益な情報と共にお会いしましょう。
Thank you for watching.
ご視聴ありがとうございました。